Inventory of O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period O.41
O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period
- Lists of Jews from Carpathian Ruthenia who were deported to camps, date empty; 88 List of deportees List of survivors List of persecuted persons List of murdered persons Typewritten; O.41/310
  - List of Jews from Nelepino who were deported, and returned home, Список осіб які були депортовані, вивезені або інтерновані і повернули додоми; 25/09/1945-25/09/1945; 3 List of deportees List of survivors; O.41/310.35
    List of Jews from Nelepino who were deported, and returned home
- Updated Schindler's Lists published in the "Doar" newspaper, 1944, 01/01/2004-01/01/2005; 40 List of survivors xerox; O.41/990
  Bruenlitz,Camp; <>,<>,<>,British Mandate For Palestine
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לוסטיג מרדכי ליבנר ויליאם
  Updated Schindler's Lists published in the "Doar" newspaper, 1944
  The list/s contain approximately 2300 names
- Section of a list of Jews in Velikiye Mosty who perished, 1941-1944, and section of a protocol of the Soviet Extraordinary State Commission regarding Nazi war crimes in Velikiye Mosty, Список семей расстрелянных евреев, имущество которых разграблено немецко-фашистскими захватчиками; 01/01/1945-01/01/1945; 2 List of murdered persons Protocol xerox; O.41/973
  Velikiye Mosty,Zolkiew,Lwow,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ע"י גינזבורג מרי
  Section of a list of Jews in Velikiye Mosty who perished, 1941-1944, and section of a protocol of the Soviet Extraordinary State Commission regarding Nazi war crimes in Velikiye Mosty
- List of the Burger family members from Czechoslovakia and their fate during the Holocaust, date empty; 1 List of murdered persons List of survivors xerox; O.41/988
  <>,<>,<>,Czechoslovakia; Ravensbrueck,Camp; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Sachsenhausen,Camp,Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Burger Adolf
  List of the Burger family members from Czechoslovakia and their fate during the Holocaust
- Documentation regarding the fate of the Jewish communities in the Kamenets Podolsk region during and after the Holocaust; and lists of Jews from Kunev who perished, date empty; 10 List of murdered persons List of soldiers Report Handwritten Typewritten; O.41/401
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Kunev,Pluzhnoye,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR); <>,<>,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Moisey Loyfer
  Documentation regarding the fate of the Jewish communities in the Kamenets Podolsk region during and after the Holocaust; and lists of Jews from Kunev who perished Includes: -List of cities and towns in the Kamenets-Podolsk region where Jews were murdered. After the war some of the communities were reestablished and others not. -List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Kunev, who died in battle, or were considered missing. -List of Kunev residents who perished. The lists were prepared by Loifer Moisey Volfovich.
  - List of Jews from Kunev who perished, 1941-1942, Список семей евреев расстрелянных и замученных фашистскими оккупантами в 1941-42 гг в с. Куневе Изяславского района и захороненных в братских могилах в с. Куневе и с. Сторониче; date empty; 5 List of murdered persons; O.41/401.1
    Kunev,Pluzhnoye,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR); Storonichi,vicinity,Murder Site,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jews from Kunev who perished, 1941-1942
    The list/s contain approximately 152 names
  - List of Jewish soldiers from Kunev, who died in battle, 1941-1945, Список громодян с. Кунів, Ізяславського району, призванних на військову службу плужиннським райвоенкомтом і загинувших на фронтах Великоі Віттчанянноі війни 1941-1945 років; 1968-1988; 2 List of murdered persons List of soldiers; O.41/401.2
    Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Kunev,Pluzhnoye,Kamenets Podolsk,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jewish soldiers from Kunev, who died in battle, 1941-1945
- Confirmation that Zlotnikov Reuven was a partisan and killed in 1942, 1947-1949; 2 Personal documents Certification Newspaper clippings Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/456
  Partisans - Jews; Rudnya,Rudnya,Smolensk,Russia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by זלוטניקוב, מושקוביץ
  Confirmation that Zlotnikov Reuven was a partisan and killed in 1942. In the file there is also a press clipping on the building of a memorial in Rudnya, in 1965.
- List of Jews from Pabjanice who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; 7 List of murdered persons Original Handwritten; O.41/967
  Pabjanice,Lask,Lodz,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by דזיאלושינסקי ליאון
  List of Jews from Pabjanice who perished during the Holocaust
  The list/s contain approximately 584 names
- Confirmation by the Jewish community regarding the death of Arpad Mueller, from Levice, who perished in Altmuehldorf, 05/10/1944, 30/10/1948-30/10/1948; 1 Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/428
  Levice,Tekov,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Altmuehldorf,Oberbayern,Bavaria,Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מילר מגדה
  Confirmation by the Jewish community regarding the death of Arpad Mueller, from Levice, who perished in Altmuehldorf, 05/10/1944
- Confirmation issued by the American Red Cross regarding the deportation of members of the Fulder family from Berlin to Auschwitz, 12/03/1943, 24/03/1995-24/03/1995; 1 Personal documents Certification xerox; O.41/432
  Berlin,Berlin,Berlin,Germany; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אמיר חנה
  Confirmation issued by the American Red Cross regarding the deportation of members of the Fulder family from Berlin to Auschwitz, 12/03/1943 Confirmation issued by the American Red Cross regarding the deportation of Gustav Fulder, Ida (Naumberg) Fulder, Eva Sophie Fulder and Fritz Moses Fulder from Berlin to Auschwitz, 12/03/1943, and regarding the death of Gustav Fulder in Auschwitz, 13/04/1943.
- JNF Timisoara certificate dated 28/09/48 confirming two trees were planted in Israel honoring of Sura Kronberger and Samuel Kronburger, who perished, 28/09/1948-28/09/1948; 2 Personal documents Record of murdered persons Official documentation xerox Original Handwritten; O.41/435
  Timisoara,Timis-Torontal,Banat,Romania; JNF - Keren Kayemet Le'Israel, Jewish National Fund
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by בק יהודית
  JNF Timisoara certificate dated 28/09/48 confirming two trees were planted in Israel honoring of Sura Kronberger and Samuel Kronburger, who perished
- Documentation regarding the fate of Elias Loewenwirth, born in Irsava, who perished in Dachau camp, 11/02/1945, 07/02/1956-23/05/1957; 5 Personal documents Letter Record of murdered persons Certification xerox; O.41/423
  Fossoli di Carpi,Camp; <>,<>,<>,France; <>,<>,<>,Switzerland; Dachau,Camp,Germany; Bergen Belsen,Camp,Germany; Sachsenhausen,Camp,Germany; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ראובני הלנה
  Documentation regarding the fate of Elias Loewenwirth, born in Irsava, who perished in Dachau camp, 11/02/1945 Confirmations issued by the Swiss Red Cross organization, the Union of Jewish Communities in Italy, and the French Embassy in Germany, 1956-1957, regarding the fate of Elias Loewenwirth, who was detained in Italy and deported to Fossoli di Carpi camp, 1944 and then his transfer to Auschwitz, Bergen-Belsen, Sachsenhausen and Dachau camp, where he perished, 11/02/1945.
- List of Jews from the Mohacs Ghetto who perished in Auschwitz, 1944 or in labor battalions, date empty; 10 List of murdered persons List of ghetto inmates xerox; O.41/444
  Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Mohacs,Ghetto,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Ungar Lajos Budapest VII. Sip u. 12 Magyarorszag
  List of Jews from the Mohacs Ghetto who perished in Auschwitz, 1944 or in labor battalions
- Documentation regarding the fate of the Mayer, Kadisch and Kolitz family members from Germany who perished during the Holocaust, 01/02/1946-02/12/1948; 9 Personal documents Certification Letter Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/447
  Search for relatives; Search for missing people; Berlin,Berlin,Berlin,Germany; Jordanbad,DP CAMP,Germany; <>,<>,<>,Czechoslovakia; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מונטר סילביה וארנסט
  Documentation regarding the fate of the Mayer, Kadisch and Kolitz family members from Germany who perished during the Holocaust - Letters issued by the UNRRA Missing Persons Bureau, regarding the fate of Emma Anna (Drexler) Meyer, who was born in Czechoslovakia during the Holocaust; - Letters issued by the UNRRA Missing Persons Bureau, 03/06/1946 and 19/06/1946, regarding the fate of Helene Wertheimer, who stayed in Jordanbad DP camp after the liberation; - Confirmation issued by the Jewish community in Berlin, 02/12/1948, regarding the fate of Paula (Block) Kadisch, Rudolf Kadisch and Gertrud (Bresch) Kolitz, who were deported to Auschwitz, 1943.
- Documentation regarding the fate of Oskar Meister Rubel and Alfons Meister, from Leipzig, who perished in Auschwitz and Majdanek camps, 1942, 07/12/1990-21/11/1995; The file was created by International Tracing Service; 3 Personal documents Record of murdered persons Certification xerox; O.41/439
  Leipzig,Leipzig,Saxony,Germany; Majdanek,Camp,Poland; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Wildgoose Maurice
  Documentation regarding the fate of Oskar Meister Rubel and Alfons Meister, from Leipzig, who perished in Auschwitz and Majdanek camps, 1942 - Confirmation issued by the National Museum in Majdanek, 21/11/1995, regarding Alfons Meister, born in Leipzig, an inmate in Majdanek, 1942 and his death in camp, 01/12/1942; - Confirmation issued by the ITS in Arolsen, 07/12/1990, regarding Oskar Meister Rubel, born in Leipzig, and who perished in Auschwitz, 10/09/1942.
- Partial list of Jews from Nevel who were murdered, in Golubaya Dacha, 1941, Невель Псковской области, Частичный список евреев, погибших на Голубой Даче; date empty; The file was created by מסרסקיה תמרה Masarskaya Tamara; 13 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/463
  Nevel,Nevel,Kalinin,Russia (USSR); Golubaya Dacha Area,forest,Murder Site,Russia (USSR)
  Partial list of Jews from Nevel who were murdered, in Golubaya Dacha, 1941
- Letter by Ilia Imyanitov regarding the Vilna Gymnasium, including a group photograph of pupils and teachers, 1937-1938; most of the people perished during the Holocaust, date empty; 4 Personal documents Letter Photograph Record of murdered persons Record of survivors Handwritten, original Original and Xerox; O.41/476
  Jewish teachers; Schools; Wilno,Wilno,Wilno,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אימיאניטוב איליה
  Letter by Ilia Imyanitov regarding the Vilna Gymnasium, including a group photograph of pupils and teachers, 1937-1938; most of the people perished during the Holocaust
- List of Wolff Ben Elazar and Moshe Ben Gompritz Halevi's relatives, who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by the submitter, date empty; 4 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/451
  <>,<>,<>,The Netherlands; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Bergen Belsen,Camp,Germany; Dachau,Camp,Germany; Sobibor,Extermination Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by וולף מקס
  List of Wolff Ben Elazar and Moshe Ben Gompritz Halevi's relatives, who perished during the Holocaust, prepared by the submitter
  The list/s contain approximately 188 names
- List of Jews who labored in an F.K.S. company factory, date empty; 3 List of persecuted persons List of ghetto inmates Original; O.41/976
  Rowno,Ghetto
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by קלייר ויינברג, ניו-יורק, ארה"ב
  List of Jews who labored in an F.K.S. company factory List of Jews who labored in an F.K.S. company factory, apparently in the Rowno Ghetto.
- Lists of Jews from Kiev who were murdered in Babiy Yar, submitted by relatives, Погибли в Бабьем Яре; date empty; 303 List of murdered persons Typewritten copy; O.41/955
  Babi Yar,Murder Site; Kiev,Kiev City,Kiev,Ukraine (USSR)
  Lists of Jews from Kiev who were murdered in Babiy Yar, submitted by relatives The lists include details about the submitters of the information.
- Lists of Jews from Tukums who perished, or who died in battle, date empty; The file was created by יעקב קרסין Yakov Karasin; 10 List of murdered persons List of soldiers Typewritten copy; O.41/457
  Tukums,Tukuma,Zemgale,Latvia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by הירש (צבי) מיזשטם
  Lists of Jews from Tukums who perished, or who died in battle Lists were prepared for the book: Jews of Tukum City, Latvia, edited by Yakov Karasin. ([s.l.]: Y. Karasin, 2002) Call number in the Yad Vashem library is T-1256.
- List of Jews from Krivoye Ozero, who were murdered, 29/08/1941; the names appear on a memorial stone established in their memory, date empty; 2 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/424
  Bequeathing the Holocaust; Commemoration; Monuments; Krivoye Ozero,Krivoye Ozero,Odessa,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ריידמן יפים
  List of Jews from Krivoye Ozero, who were murdered, 29/08/1941; the names appear on a memorial stone established in their memory Includes a photograph of the memorial stone.
- Confirmation by the local authority in Nemecka Poruba regarding the deportation of Zelmanovic family members from Nemecka Poruba to Poland, 1942, and certification of their death, 22/01/1947-22/01/1947; The file was created by Miestny narodny vybor v Nemeckej Porube, okres Sobrance; 1 Personal documents Certification xerox; O.41/433
  Nemecka Poruba,Uzhorod,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; <>,<>,<>,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by זלמנוביץ לאופולד
  Confirmation by the local authority in Nemecka Poruba regarding the deportation of Zelmanovic family members from Nemecka Poruba to Poland, 1942, and certification of their death
- List of Jews from Skierniewice who perished in Skierniewice, Piotrkow Trybunalski, Rawa Mazowiecka and Warszaw, 1939-1943, 07/07/1984-22/10/1984; 9 List of murdered persons Typewritten Typewritten copy; O.41/440
  Skierniewice,Skierniewice,Warszawa,Poland; Piotrkow Trybunalski,Piotrkow,Lodz,Poland; Rawa Mazowiecka,Rawa Mazowiecka,Warszawa,Poland; Warszawa,Warszawa,Warszawa,Poland
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from OKREGOWA KOMISJA BADANIA ZBRODNI PRZECIWKO NARODOWI POLSKIEMU - OKBZPNP, POZNAN, POLAND
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by יד ושם
  List of Jews from Skierniewice who perished in Skierniewice, Piotrkow Trybunalski, Rawa Mazowiecka and Warszaw, 1939-1943 The lists were prepared by the regional Commission for the Investigation of Nazi War Crimes in Lodz, 1984.
  The list/s contain approximately 71 names
- List of Jews from Gyor who perished, 1944-1945, 1996-1996; 26 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/445
  Hungarian Jews; Gyor,Gyor Moson es Pozsony,<>,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ע"י שגרירות ישראל בודפשט
  List of Jews from Gyor who perished, 1944-1945 The list was prepared by the Hungarian National Resistance Union, based on various sources.
  The list/s contain approximately 3845 names
- Confirmation issued by the International Tracing Service (ITS) in Arolsen regarding the death of Ruth Aftergut, born in Berlin, Germany, 1916, perished in Auschwitz, 01/11/1942, 23/05/1990-23/05/1990; 1 Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/436
  Warszawa,Warszawa,Warszawa,Poland; Berlin,Berlin,Berlin,Germany; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland; Arolsen,Kassel,Hesse-Nassau,Germany
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from INTERNATIONAL TRACING SERVICE, AROLSEN - ITS
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Pinhas Aftergot
  Confirmation issued by the International Tracing Service (ITS) in Arolsen regarding the death of Ruth Aftergut, born in Berlin, Germany, 1916, perished in Auschwitz, 01/11/1942
- Lists of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Chernigov, and Kremenchug, who died in battle, 1941-1945, 1987-1991; 48 List of murdered persons List of soldiers Original Typewritten; O.41/459
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Kremenchug,Kremenchug City,Poltava,Ukraine (USSR); Chernigov,Chernigov City,Chernigov,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Zaslavski Isaak
  Lists of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Chernigov, and Kremenchug, who died in battle, 1941-1945
  - List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Chernigov, who died in battle, 1941-1945, Светлой памяти евреев-черниговцев, павших на фронтах Великой Отечественной войны 1941-1945 годов; 1987-1991; 18 List of murdered persons List of soldiers; O.41/459.1
    Chernigov,Chernigov City,Chernigov,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Chernigov, who died in battle, 1941-1945
    The list/s contain approximately 630 names
  - List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Kremenchug, who died in battle, 1941-1945, Подвиг кременчужан бессмертен - Книга вечной памяти; 1987-1991; 28 List of murdered persons List of soldiers; O.41/459.2
    Kremenchug,Kremenchug City,Poltava,Ukraine (USSR)
    List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Kremenchug, who died in battle, 1941-1945
    The list/s contain approximately 193 names
- List of Jews from Temerin who were murdered in Zabalj, 09/01/1942, date empty; 4 List of murdered persons Record of survivors xerox; O.41/465
  Temerin,<>,Backa - Vojvodina,Yugoslavia; Zabalj,<>,Backa - Vojvodina,Yugoslavia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לוקר צבי
  List of Jews from Temerin who were murdered in Zabalj, 09/01/1942 The names of the survivors appear on p. 2148.
- List of Jews from Mezokovesd and settlements in the vicinity who perished in the Holocaust, and a list of survivors who contributed toward the establishment of a memorial monument at Mezokovesd, 1946-1946; 154 Yizkor book List of murdered persons List of survivors Original; O.41/695
  Commemoration; Bequeathing the Holocaust; Mezokovesd,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Bogacs,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szomolya,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szentistvan,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Szihalom,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Novaj,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Borsodszemere,Borsod,<>,Hungary; Borsodivanka,Borsod,<>,Hungary
  List of Jews from Mezokovesd and settlements in the vicinity who perished in the Holocaust, and a list of survivors who contributed toward the establishment of a memorial monument at Mezokovesd - List of Jews from Mezokovesd and settlements in the vicinity who perished in the Holocaust; - List of survivors from Mezokovesd who contributed toward the establishment of a memorial monument at Mezokovesd (pp. 754-759).
- Documentation regarding the fate of the Prins, Van Klaveren and Peereboom family members, from the Netherlands, who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; 25 Personal documents Certification Letter Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/452
  Westerbork,Camp,The Netherlands; Graeditz,Camp,Germany; Bergen Belsen,Camp,Germany; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by רזי מרדכי
  Documentation regarding the fate of the Prins, Van Klaveren and Peereboom family members, from the Netherlands, who perished during the Holocaust - Transfer of the deportees from Westerbork camp to Auschwitz, Bergen-Belsen and Graeditz camps, where the deportees perished; - Information was sent by the Dutch Red Cross organization, at the request of J. Van Klaveren, 1996.
- List of Jews from Levoca who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; 2 List of murdered persons Names of Jewish partisans xerox; O.41/968
  Levoca,Spis,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
  List of Jews from Levoca who perished during the Holocaust
  The list/s contain approximately 409 names
- List of Jews from Valasske Mezirici who perished during the Holocaust, List of Jews killed in the Holocaust from Valasske Mezirici and District - Czechoslovakia; 01/01/2004-01/01/2004; The file was created by Michael Honey; 7 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/974
  Valasske Mezirici,Valasske Mezirici,Moravia-Silesia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by הני מיכאל
  List of Jews from Valasske Mezirici who perished during the Holocaust
- Confirmation from the Regional State Archive in Gomel that the name of Movsha Tzenter from Mozyr is included on the list of those who were murdered by the Nazis, dated 1991, 30/05/1991-30/05/1991; 3 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons Original and Xerox; O.41/956
  Rabbis; Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
  The material was aquired by Yad Vashem from FILIAL GOSUDARSTVENNOGO ARKHIVA GOMELSKOY OBLASTI V g. MOZYR
  Confirmation from the Regional State Archive in Gomel that the name of Movsha Tzenter from Mozyr is included on the list of those who were murdered by the Nazis, dated 1991
- Registration page of Rachel Leuchter in Stutthof camp, 10/09/1944, 10/09/1944-10/09/1944; 1 Personal documents xerox; O.41/430
  Stutthof,Camp
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מנור גניה
  Registration page of Rachel Leuchter in Stutthof camp, 10/09/1944
- List of prison inmates in Banska Bystrica camp who were murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945, Zoznam zavrazdenych vaznov v banskobystrickom koncentraku,ktori boli zastreleni v Kremnicke; 03/03/1947-03/03/1947; 27 Official documentation Personal records Letter List of murdered persons Report Statistical data Memoirs xerox; O.41/434
  Banska Bystrica,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Kremnicka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Nemecka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Slovak National Uprising, 1944
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Muzeum SNP,97559, Banska Bystrica, Kapitulska 23
  List of prison inmates in Banska Bystrica camp who were murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945 Included in the file: - Explanation regarding the list of the people who were murdered; - Memoirs of Mattitiyahu Glombush and Stefan Simon; - Additional documentation.
  - List of the Banska Bystrica prison inmates murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945, Zoznam zavrazdenych vaznov v banskobystrickom koncentraku,ktori boli zastreleni v Kremnicke; 03/03/1947-03/03/1947; 12 List of murdered persons; O.41/434.1
    Banska Bystrica,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Kremnicka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia; Nemecka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
    List of the Banska Bystrica prison inmates murdered in Kremnicka, 11/1944-01/1945 - Appendix to the list and explanation by Mattityahu Galambush (pp. 1666-1667).
    The list/s contain approximately 372 names
- List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Bobruysk, who died in battle, 1941-1945, date empty; 18 List of murdered persons List of soldiers xerox; O.41/458
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Bobruysk,Bobruysk City,Mogilev,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ברונקה קליבנסקי
  List of Jewish Red Army soldiers from Bobruysk, who died in battle, 1941-1945
  The list/s contain approximately 253 names
- List of Jews murdered and buried in mass graves in Kremnicka, 05/11/1944-09/02/1945, Obete izraelskeho povodu zavrazdene fasistami a pochovane v hromadnych hroboch pri obci Kremnicka v dobe od 5.11.1944-19.02.1945; 01/11/1996-30/11/1996; 10 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/449
  Mass graves; Kremnicka,Zvolen,Slovakia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by טוט דזידר
  List of Jews murdered and buried in mass graves in Kremnicka, 05/11/1944-09/02/1945
  The list/s contain approximately 240 names